Hi, I'm Avigail Laing, and I got into every single college I applied to,
including NYU, Rice, and Vanderbilt.
And Vanderbilt gave me a full tuition scholarship that only
goes to under 1% of applicants.
In total, I earned over $600,000 in merit scholarship offers, and I was
named a US presidential scholar, one of only 161 chosen annually in the
country each year, but I didn't found a nonprofit or do any crazy extracurriculars.
So how did I do it?
Well, I figured out how to write really good college essays, the kind that make
admissions officers actually read all the way through and then walk away knowing
what value I bring to their college as a student.
Since then, I've taught that same strategy to over a thousand students,
helping them write college essays that have gotten them into schools like Penn,
Dartmouth, UC Berkeley with a Regents Scholarship, Cornell, NYU with a full
ride twice, Georgetown, West Point, UCLA, USC, and so many more.
In the class of 2026 alone, four of my students got full ride scholarships.
One to NYU with housing included, one to NYU Shanghai for $71,000 a year,
another to Rhodes College, and one who got full rides to both
Virginia Tech and George Mason.
And my other students have earned countless merit scholarships from
schools like UCSD, TCU, U Miami, and so many others, which are all included
in the results section of my website.
I know exactly how overwhelming the college essay process can be, and my
job is taking the guesswork out of that process and making it easy and
straightforward for you so that when you're done with your essays, you know
for sure that you did them right, that they're going to move the needle
in a positive direction for you, and that admissions officers are going
to see that you're an asset to their school when they read those essays.
So how do you get my help?
Well, there are three ways, depending on how much help you want.
If you want live one-on-one support from me to get help writing your essay,
brainstorming, figuring out how to do supplementals, I offer one-on-one coaching.
You can either book a single session or I offer discounted packages with
multiple sessions where I will walk you through the entire process of
creating your Common App essay, your supplementals, or both.
The packages are definitely my most popular option because they give you help
throughout every single step of the process.
I'll be there with you when you're brainstorming.
I'll help you pick a good topic, write your outlines, and make sure that
your essays include a level of detail that moves the needle in
a positive direction for you.
The packages include unlimited email support for me in between every
call, and I run all the calls myself.
I don't have a team.
I give you all the feedback myself.
And at the end of every call, you'll have a PDF and document with all
of the recommendations that I gave you, edits, and everything that we worked on.
If scheduling is hard for you and you'd rather not do a call, I also offer
asynchronous written edits on your essays.
So whether you need me just to do like a one-time essay edit and send you back
feedback within 48 hours and edits, I can do that, or I also have editing
packages where I will give you multiple revisions of your Common
App essay, supplementals, or both.
This is a better option for you if you have like a really busy schedule
and you are not sure if you'll be able to easily schedule calls with me.
Because I can give you the same level of feedback and the same amount
of edits just without you having the hassle of scheduling this way.
I also have a hybrid option where if you need help just brainstorming
your topic and then want written edits on it after that, we can just do
one call and then four written edits, if that works better for you too.
And finally, if you want to work on this process on your own, I took
literally everything that I do with my one-on-one students, the whole
process of how to write a good college essay and turned it into a 36
document system with documents walking you through every single step of how
to write a good college essay and your supplementals too.
It includes documents on how to brainstorm, how to come up with a good
topic, how to create an outline, how to include the right details
in your outline, how to make sure your essay doesn't sound like AI,
how to emulate the writing style of the best essays that I've read.
And it includes supplemental packs for over 12 separate schools in it too.
And finally, it also has a checklist that you can run your
essay through before submission to make sure that it does everything right.
It is literally the most helpful thing I've put together and has all the
value you could possibly need, all the advice for writing your essays
from start to finish, genuinely everything that you need.
It's called the Yes Pile Method or my full college essay writing system.
And you can find it here on my store.
The best part of it is that it actually comes with a document with
multiple sample essays from my students who have gotten into top schools
like Dartmouth and even my own Common App Essay and my own supplementals
so that you can see what winning essays did and then
figure out how to replicate that.
It literally goes through all seven Common App prompts and has a sample
essay for each one so that you can see how to do what the winning students did.
Essay coaching is one of the best investments that you could possibly make
because for such a small price, you could possibly win tens of thousands
of dollars in scholarship money per year, which makes a life or death
difference when it comes to being able to pay off your college loans.
I've seen so many of my students get into schools that they said
their GPA wasn't good enough for because of their essays.
And I've also seen so many of my students get amazing
scholarships that have really lightened the financial pressure on them.
I would love to help you through this process and make it as
easy and painless for you as I can.
So you can read more on my website to figure out how to book with me.
Pick whichever package works best for you.
And if you have any questions, feel free to email
avigaillaing@gmail.com and I would love to answer and work with you this season.
Whichever way you're getting help, you are going to be getting the same
strategy that got me into every single college I applied to.
And I know it's going to make a difference for you.
I can't wait to work together.